So I grew up in East Los Angeles,
لقد نشآت في شرقي لوس آنجلوس،
not even realizing I was poor.
ولم أكن أدرك أنني فقيرة.
My dad was a high-ranking gang member who ran the streets.
لقد كان أبي عضو في إحدى العصابات رفيعة المستوى في المنطقة
Everyone knew who I was,
الكل كان يعلم من أكون،
so I thought I was a pretty big deal, and I was protected,
لذا اعتقدت أني ذو شأن كبير، وأنني كنت بأمان !
and even though my dad spent most of my life
ومع أن أبي أمضى معظم حياته
in and out of jail,
داخل أو خارج من السجن
I had an amazing mom who was just fiercely independent.
كانت لدي أم رائعة وكانت مستقلة بشدة .
She worked at the local high school
لقد عمِلَت في الثانوية المحلية
as a secretary in the dean's office,
كسكرتيرة في مكتب العميد،
so she got to see all the kids that got thrown out of class,
لذا قد رأت كل الطلاب الذين طردوا من الصفوف،
for whatever reason, who were waiting to be disciplined.
لأي سبب كان، ينتظرون ليُأنّبوا .
Man, her office was packed.
مكتبها كان مكتظاً !
So, see, kids like us, we have a lot of things to deal with
كما ترون، أطفالٌ مثلنا، لدينا الكثير لنتعامل معه
outside of school,
خارج المدرسة،
and sometimes we're just not ready to focus.
وأحياناً، لا نكون جاهزين للتركيز.
But that doesn't mean that we can't.
لكن هذا لا يعني أننا لا نستطيع التركيز.
It just takes a little bit more.
ولكن يحتاج هذا جهدا أكبر بقليل.
Like, I remember one day I found my dad
أتذكر مثلاً أني وجدت والدي يوماً
convulsing, foaming at the mouth,
يرتعش، و رغوة في فمه،
OD-ing on the bathroom floor.
ملقى على أرض الحمام.
Really, do you think that doing my homework that night
أحقاً تعتقد أن وظائفي المدرسية تلك اليلة كانت
was at the top of my priority list?
على قائمة أولوياتي ؟!
Not so much.
ليس لهذا الحد .
But I really needed a support network,
لكني حقاً كنت بحاجة لشبكة دعم،
a group of people who were going to help me
مجموعة من الأشخاص ليقوموا بمساعدتي
make sure that I wasn't going to be
لأتأكد من أني لن أكون
a victim of my own circumstance,
ضحية ظروفي الخاصة،
that they were going to push me
ليدفعوني لأقوم بأشياء
beyond what I even thought I could do.
لم أكن حتى أفكّر أني قادرة عليها.
I needed teachers, in the classroom, every day,
لقد كنت بحاجة لمدرّسين، في الصف، كل يوم،
who were going to say, "You can move beyond that."
الذين سيقولون لي، "يمكنك تحقيق أكثر من ذلك."
And unfortunately, the local junior high
وللأسف، المدرسة المحلية
was not going to offer that.
لم تكن ستقدّم لي هذا الدعم.
It was gang-infested, huge teacher turnover rate.
كانت تنتشر فيها العصابات، ومعدل ترك المعملين للعمل عالٍ .
So my mom said, "You're going on a bus
لذا قالت أمي :ستذهبين في حافلة
an hour and a half away from where we live every day."
لمسافة ساعة ونصف من مكان إقامتنا، كل يوم. "
So for the next two years, that's what I did.
وخلال السنتنين اللاحقتين، هذا ما فعلته .
I took a school bus to the fancy side of town.
أخذت حافلة مدرسة إلى الطرف الراقي من المدينة.
And eventually, I ended up at a school
وفي النهاية، وجدت نفسي في مدرسة
where there was a mixture.
فيها خليط.
There were some people who were really gang-affiliated,
كان هناك هؤلاء الأشخاص التابعين فعلاً لعصابات،
and then there were those of us
وكان هناك النوع الآخر، نحن
really trying to make it to high school.
الذين نحاول أن نصل الى الثانوية.
Well, trying to stay out of trouble was a little unavoidable.
و محاولتك لتفادي المشاكل، كانت لا مفرّ منها.
You had to survive.
عليك أن تبقى.
You just had to do things sometimes.
كان عليك أن تقوم بأشياء في بعض الأحيان.
So there were a lot of teachers who were like,
لذا كثير من المعلمين كانوا يقولون،
"She's never going to make it.
"لن تستطيع هذه الفتاة الصمود.
She has an issue with authority.
إن لديها مشكلة مع السلطة.
She's not going to go anywhere."
لن تذهب إلى أي مكان."
Some teachers completely wrote me off as a lost cause.
حتى أن بعض المدرسين شطبني لأنني كنت قضية خاسرة.
But then, they were very surprised
لكن لاحقاً، كانوا متفاجئين جداً
when I graduated from high school.
عندما تخرجت من الثانوية.
I was accepted to Pepperdine University,
لقد قُبلت في جامعة "بيبرداين"،
and I came back to the same school that I attended
وعدت إلى نفس المدرسة التي درست بها
to be a special ed assistant.
لأكون مساعدة للحالات الخاصة.
And then I told them, "I want to be a teacher."
وعندها قلت لهم : أريد أن أكون معلّمة.
And boy, they were like, "What? Why?
ويا إلهي ، لقد كانو مصدومين وقالوا : ماذا؟ لماذا ؟ !
Why would you want to do that?"
لماذا تريدين القيام بهذا؟ "
So I began my teaching career
فبدأت مسيرتي المهنية في التدريس
at the exact same middle school that I attended,
في نفس وذات المدرسة التي درست فيها،
and I really wanted to try to save more kids
وحقاً كنت أريد محاولة مساعدة العديد من الأطفال
who were just like me.
الذين كانوا مثلي.
And so every year, I share my background with my kids,
لذا كل عام، أشارك قصتي مع طلابي،
because they need to know that everyone has a story,
لأنهم يجب أن يعلموا أن لكل شخص قصة،
everyone has a struggle,
الكل لديه مصاعب،
and everyone needs help along the way.
والكل يحتاج إلى المساعدة على طول الطريق.
And I am going to be their help along the way.
وأنا سأكون مساعدتهم على طول الطريق.
So as a rookie teacher, I created opportunity.
لذا، كوني مدرّسة مبتدأة، قد خلقت فرصة،
I had a kid one day come into my class
قد جاء طالبٌ إلى صفي يوماً
having been stabbed the night before.
كان قد تعرض للطعن في الليلة السابقة.
I was like, "You need to go to a hospital,
قلت له "يجب أن تذهب إلى المستشفى،
the school nurse, something."
ممرضة المدرسة، أي شيئ. "
He's like, "No, Miss, I'm not going.
قال لي : لا يا آنسة، لن أذهب.
I need to be in class because I need to graduate."
عليّ أن أكون في الصف لأني أحتاج أن أتخرج "
So he knew that I was not going to let him be a victim
فقد علمَ أنني لن أدعه يكون ضحية
of his circumstance,
لظروفه الخاصة،
but we were going to push forward and keep moving on.
لكن كنا سنندفع ونكمل في طريقنا.
And this idea of creating a safe haven for our kids
وهذه الفكرة في خلق ملاذ آمن لأطفالنا
and getting to know exactly what they're going through,
وأن نعلم تماماً مالذي يخوضونه،
getting to know their families -- I wanted that,
أن نتعرف على عائلاتهم -- أردت هذا بالفعل،
but I couldn't do it in a school with 1,600 kids,
لكني لم أقدر على فعله في مدرسة مع 1600 طالب،
and teachers turning over year after year after year.
ومدرسين يستسلمون سنة بعد سنة بعد سنة.
How do you get to build those relationships?
كيف ستقوم ببناء هذه العلاقات؟
So we created a new school.
لذا قمنا ببناء مدرسة جديدة.
And we created
وبنينا
the San Fernando Institute for Applied Media.
معهد سان فرنادندو لوسائل الإعلام التطبيقية.
And we made sure that we were still attached
وتأكدنا من أن نبقى مرتبطين
to our school district for funding, for support.
بمنطقتنا التعليمية للتمويل وللدعم.
But with that, we were going to gain freedom:
ومع هذا كنا سنحصل على الحرية
freedom to hire the teachers
حرية توظيف المدرّسين
that we knew were going to be effective;
الذين نعلم أنهم سيكونون فعّالين،
freedom to control the curriculum
حرية التحكم بالمناهج
so that we're not doing lesson 1.2 on page five, no;
لكي لا ندرّس الدرس رقم 1.2 في الصفحة كذا .. لأ
and freedom to control a budget,
وحرية التحكم بالموازنة،
to spend money where it matters,
لإنفاق المال في مكانها،
not how a district or a state says you have to do it.
ليس كما تقول المقاطعة أو الولاية لنا أن ننفقها.
We wanted those freedoms.
أردنا أن نحصل على هذه الحريات.
But now, shifting an entire paradigm,
ولكن الآن، تحويل نظام كامل،
it hasn't been an easy journey, nor is it even complete.
لم يكن رحلة سهلة، وليس مكتملاً بعد.
But we had to do it.
ولكن كان علينا فعله.
Our community deserved a new way of doing things.
مجتمعنا يستحق طريقة جديدة في فعل الأمور
And as the very first pilot middle school
وكأول المدارس المتوسطة التجريبية
in all of Los Angeles Unified School District,
في كل المقاطعات التعليمية في لوس انجلوس،
you better believe there was some opposition.
عليك تصديق أنه كان هناك بعض المعارضة.
And it was out of fear --
وقد كانت ناتجة عن الخوف --
fear of, well, what if they get it wrong?
الخوف من، حسن ماذا إذا فعلوها بشكل خاطئ؟
Yeah, what if we get it wrong?
أجل، ماذا إذا فعلناها بشكل خاطئ؟
But what if we get it right?
ولكن ماذا إذا فعلناها بشكل صحيح ؟
And we did.
وهذا الذي فعلناه.
So even though teachers were against it
لذا مع أن المدرسين كانوا ضدها
because we employ one-year contracts --
لأننا وظفنا بعقود لسنة واحدة --
you can't teach, or you don't want to teach,
إن كنت لا تستطيع التدريس أو لا تريد التدريس،
you don't get to be at my school with my kids.
فلن تكون في مدرستي ومع أطفالي.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So in our third year, how did we do it?
في عامنا الثالث، كيف فعلناها؟
Well, we're making school worth coming to every day.
حسن، نحن نجعل من المدرسة شيئ يستحق القدوم من أجله كل يوم.
We make our kids feel like they matter to us.
نشعر أطفالنا بأنهم يهموننا.
We make our curriculum rigorous and relevant to them,
نجعل مناهجنا دقيقة وذات صلة بهم،
and they use all the technology that they're used to.
ويستعملون كل التكنلوجيا المتعودون عليها.
Laptops, computers, tablets -- you name it, they have it.
لابتوبات، كومبيوترات، حواسيب لوحية -- سمّ ما شئت، جميعها لديهم.
Animation, software, moviemaking software, they have it all.
برامج رسوم، وبرمجيات حواسب و برامج لصنع الأفلام، جميعها لديهم.
And because we connect it to what they're doing —
ولأننا نربطها بالذي يفعلونه --
For example, they made public service announcements
مثلاً، قد عملوا إعلانات للخدمة العامة
for the Cancer Society.
لمرضى السرطان.
These were played in the local trolley system.
هذه الإعلانات عُرضت في نظام العربات المحلية.
Teaching elements of persuasion,
تدريس عناصر الإقناع ؟!
it doesn't get any more real than that.
لن تكون أكثر واقعية من ذلك .
Our state test scores have gone up
ارتفعت نتائج اختباراتنا
more than 80 points since we've become our own school.
لأكثر من 80 نقطة منذ أن أصبحنا في مدرستنا الخاصة.
But it's taken all stakeholders, working together --
ولكن هذا يتطلب كل أصحاب المصالح أن يعملوا معاً --
teachers and principals on one-year contracts,
مدرسين، مدراء، على عقود لسنة واحدة،
working over and above and beyond their contract hours
يعملون أكثر فأكثر وبما يفوق ساعات العمل الموجودة في العقد
without compensation.
دون تعويض.
And it takes a school board member
وإنها تتطلب عضو من مجلس المدرسة
who is going to lobby for you and say,
ليأتي ليعقب لصالحك ويقول :
"Know, the district is trying to impose this,
إعلم أن المقاطعة تحاول فعل هذا،
but you have the freedom to do otherwise."
ولكن لديك حرية الخيار بفعل العكس."
And it takes an active parent center
وإنها تتطلب مركز نشيط للأهل
who is not only there, showing a presence every day,
ليس فقط ليتواجد هناك ليثبت حضوره
but who is part of our governance,
وإنما ليكون جزء من الإدارة،
making decisions for their kids, our kids.
يصنع القرارات لأطفاله، أطفالنا.
Because why should our students have to go
لأنه لماذا على طلابنا أن يذهبوا
so far away from where they live?
بعيداً جداً عن حيث يقطنون؟
They deserve a quality school in their neighborhood,
إنهم يستحقون مدرسة ذات جودة في منطقتهم،
a school that they can be proud to say they attend,
مدرسة حيث سيقولون بفخر أنهم ينتمون لها ،
and a school that the community can be proud of as well,
ومدرسة حيث المجتمع سيكون فخورا بها أيضاً،
and they need teachers to fight for them every day
وهم يحتاجون لمدرسين ليقاتلوا من أجلهم كل يوم
and empower them to move beyond their circumstances.
ويدفعونهم ليتحركوا بما يفوق ظروفهم.
Because it's time that kids like me
لأنه الوقت لأطفال مثلي
stop being the exception, and we become the norm.
أن لا نكون حالة خاصة بعد الآن، وأن نكون المعيار.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)